# Marcelo Tavora

#### Web Developer | Front-end Developer | React | Full-Stack Developer

Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil

marcelovtneves@gmail.com | +55 85 99407-8873

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marcelovtn | Portfolio: www.marcelotavora.vercel.app/

# **Professional Summary**

Minimalist and Organized Developer who strives to deliver their best and aims to improve mainly in web development and test their knowledge by developing SaaS solutions. My main expertise is in Front-end development with React. is and Back-end with Node.

## **Work Experience**

## **Febracis Coaching**

Mid level Front-End Developer | August 2024 - Present

- Develop front-end applications using React.js with Material UI, Formik, Context, and TypeScript
- Implement agile methodologies (Scrum, Kanban) for efficient team collaboration
- Develop full-stack features using React and Node
- Review code through pull requests to maintain quality standards
- Transform Figma designs into responsive, functional interfaces

## Canix Soluções em TI

Mid level Full-Stack Developer | January 2023 - November 2024

- Led front-end development using React.js with PrimeReact, React Query, and Redux
- Implemented integration testing with JUnit (back-end) and Jest (front-end)
- · Architected and organized front-end projects for optimal performance
- Managed task distribution among front-end developers
- Developed interfaces from Figma prototypes
- Organized GitHub repositories for front-end projects
- Created full-stack solutions using Spring and React.js

#### neWave Telecom

Full-Stack Developer | May 2022 - November 2022

- Developed omnichannel solution using React.js with Material UI (front-end)
- Built back-end systems with Express, PostgreSQL, and Redis

#### Unifor

Front-End Developer | February 2022 - September 2022

- Developed front-end using Angular.js and PrimeNG
- Resolved complex responsiveness issues
- Managed project architecture and implemented internationalization with i18n

#### **Edubrahub**

Front-End Developer | November 2021 - January 2022

 Refactored ERP front-end using React.js with Styled Components, Redux, and React Query

## **Five Digital Solutions**

Co-founder & Front-End Developer | August 2021 - November 2021

- Developed landing pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Acquired clients and participated in business negotiations
- Created websites from Figma prototypes
- Implemented SEO strategies for improved visibility

#### S4E

Intern Front-End Developer | March 2021 - August 2021

- Developed ERP for dental clinics using Angular.js and React.js
- Established strong foundation in Agile Methodologies and Git

## **Education**

#### Universidade de Fortaleza - UNIFOR

Systems Analysis and Development, Computer Science | August 2022 - December 2023

## Universidade de Fortaleza - UNIFOR

Computer Science | 2020 - August 2022

# Languages

- English (Professional Working)
- Portuguese (Native)